Mines and Mining Companies In Arizona and the Southwest Collection, 1855-1934
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Mines and Mining Companies In Arizona and the Southwest Collection, 1855-1934
MS 307
The bulk of the collection consist of prospectuses, reports, and correspondence, relating to Arizona mines and mining activity from 1855 - 1934. Also contains clippings, maps, some financial records, ledgers. Some of the printed materials contain photographs of the mines and environments.
2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consist of prospectuses, reports, and correspondence, relating to Arizona mines and mining activity from 1855 - 1934. Also contains clippings, maps, some financial records, ledgers. Some of the printed materials contain photographs of the mines and environments.
Access Terms
American Copper Company
Arizona Consolidated Mines Company
Copper Queen Mining Company
Crown King Mines Company
Harqua-Hala Gold Mine Company
Yaqui Copper Company
Mines and mineral resources -- Southwest, New -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Prospectus writing
Josefa and Brave Alice Mines
Prospectuses
Maps
Reports
Photographs
Container List
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Includes:
  Acme Smelting and Refining Company
  Agassiz Mining Company
  Amalgamated Gold and Copper Company
  Amargoso Mill & Mining Company
  Anita Consolidated Copper Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  American Copper Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Arizona and New Mexico Prospecting, Developing and Mining Co.
  Arizona Blue Bell Copper Company
  Arizona, Eastern and Montana Smelting, Ore Purchasing and Development Company
  Arizona Gold and Copper Company
  Arizona Gold Mining and Milling Company
  Arizona Mining and Trading Company (George Kippen Diary)
  Arizona Reduction Company Ltd.
  Arizona United Copper Company
  Arizona United Mining Company
  Atlanta Mine (see also Oversize)
  Aztec and Tyndall Gold and Silver Mining Districts
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Arizona Consolidated Mines Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Bannie Gold Mining and Milling Company
  Baumann Copper Company
  Belcher Mine Company
  Black Diamond Copper Mining Company
  Boston and Texas Copper Company
  Boston-Arizona Mining Company
  Boston Gold-Copper Mining Company
  Bradshaw Mountain Copper Mining and Smelter Company
  Braganza Gold Mining Company
  Bullwhacker Gold and Copper Company
  Bunker Hill Gold Mining Company
  Bunker Hill Group of Mines
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  C.O.D. Consolidated Mines Company
  Calumet and Arizona Mining Company
  Canada del Oro
  Capital Copper Company
  Castle Dome Exploration and Reduction Company
  Cave Mine
  Cochise Copper Mining Company
  Cochise Mining and Milling Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Consolidated Arizona Smelting Company
  Consolidated Gold & Copper Company
  Consolidated Junior Mining Company
  Consolidated King Development and Columbia Copper Co.
  Continental Consolidated Mining Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Copper Belle Mining Company
  Copper Bullion Mining Company
  Copper Crown of Arizona Mining Company
  Copper King of Arizona
  Copper Queen Mining Company (see also Oversize)
  Corona Consolidated Gold and Copper Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Crown King Mines Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  David Harum Copper Company
  Decatur Copper Mining Company
  Douglas Copper Company
  El Magistral Copper Company
  Electra Mining and Milling Company
  Esperanza Group of Gold & Copper Mines
  Eugenie Mine Federal Mining Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  George A. Treadwell Mining Company
  Gillespie Mine
  Globe-Boston Copper Mining Company
  Gold Boulder Mining Company
  Gold Creek Mining Company
  Gold Exploiting Company of America
  Gold Hills Mining Company
  Gold Run Mining & Tunnel Company
  Golden Era Gold Mining Company
  Golden Rule Copper Company
  Graham County Mining Company
  Great Peck Mine of Arizona
- Arizona mines. January 11 - May 15, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Correspondence: John to Nora Ferris, Activities at the Gillepie Mine, Canon, AZ. January 11 - May 15, 1916
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  Harquahala Gold Mine Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Harcuar Mines
  Hassayamp Gold Dredging Company
  Helena Gold Mines Company
  Holbrook Mine
  Horse Shoe Copper Mining Company
  Huachuca Consolidated Development Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Ida Waite Mine
  Illizona Mining and Development Company
  Imperial Copper Company
  Independence Consolidated Gold and Silver Mining Company
  Inspiration Consolidated Copper Company
  International Exploitation Company
  Jerome Silver-Copper Mines Corporation
  King Placer Consolidated (see Yuma Consolidated)
  King Verde Gold & Copper Company
  Kingman Gold-Silver-Lead Merger Mines CompanyHarcuar Mines
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  Josefa and Brave Alice Mines
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Lida Goldfield Mining Company
  Lime Creek Copper Company
  Lincoln Copper Mining Company
  Little Jessie Gold Mining Company
  Live Oak Copper Mining and Smelting Company
  Loma Prieta Mines Company
  Lone Pine Mining Company
  Lucky Verde Copper Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Mammoth Copper Company
  Mammoth Gold Company
  Marquette & Arizona Mining Company
  McCabe Gold Mining Company
  McKinley Mining and Development Company
  McLeod Mine Metals Milling Company
  Metals Milling Company
  Midway Consolidated Mining Company
  Mitchell Mining Company
  Model Gold Mining Company
  Morenci Copper Company
  Mormon Girl Mining Company
  Mountain Lion Mine
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Montizona Copper Company Minsutes, Vol. 1, 1818-1929
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  New York and Arizona Copper Mining and Smelting Company
  Oceanic Gold Mining Company
  Ohio and Arizona Copper Mining and Smelting Company
  Old Dominion Mining and Smelting Company
  Old Terrible Mining Company
  Ora Cobra Mining Company
  Oro Grande Mine
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Oxford gold Mines (see Oversize)
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Palace Gold & Copper Company
  Phoenix Gold Mining Company
  Picacho Blanco Mining Company
  Piles Peak Gold and Copper Mining Company
  Pittsburgh Copper Mining and Reduction Company
  Plata-Cobre Mining & Transportation Company
  Poland Extension Gold Mining & Milling Company
  Pride of Arizona Copper Company
  Princeton Copper Mining & Smelting Company
  Producer Mining & Smelting Company
  Promontorio Mining Company
  Prosperity Mining Company, Ltd.
  Pyramid Gold and Copper Mining Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Queen of Arizona Copper Company
  Quincy & Arizona Development Company
  Ray Mines
  Reliance Gold and Copper Mining Company
  Relief Gold Mining Company
  Riverside Copper Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Saddle Mountain Mining Company
  San Remo Copper Mining Company
  San Xavier Mining and Smelting Company
  Santa Rita Copper and Smelting Company
  Santa Rosa Copper Company
  Satisfaction Mine
  Sequin Gold Mining Company
  Sierra Prieta Mines Company
  Smuggler Placer Group
  Snyder Group of Copper Mines
  Standard Consolidated Copper Company
  Standard Smelting & Refining Company
  St. John Gold and Copper Co.
  South Western Mining Bureau
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  San Xavier Mines Ledger, February-December 1900
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Tom Reed, Goldroad District
  Tombstone Consolidated Mines Company, Ltd.
  Tombstone Mining Syndicate
  Treasure Hill Mining Company
  Tri-Bullion Smelting and Development Company
  Trinity Gold Mining Company
  Troy-Manhattan Copper Company
  Turkey Creek Mining Company
  Tyndall Mining Company
  Tyndall Gold and Silver Mining District (see Aztec and Tyndall Gold and Silver Mining Districts)
  Uncle Sam Copper Company
  United Mining and Exploration Company
  United Verde Copper Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Val Verde Copper Company, Ltd.
  Veiled Prophet Copper Company, Ltd.
  Vekol Mines
  Verde Chief Copper Mining Company
  Verde King Mining Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Virginia Belle Gold and Copper Mining Company
  Vulture Mine
  West Mining & Milling Company
  White Gold Mining Company
  White Hills Mines
  White Horse Mining Company
  Yellow Jacket Mines Company
  Yucca Cyanide Mining & Milling Co. Gold Mines
  Yuma Consolidated Mines and Mill Company
- Arizona mines. 1855-1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Yuma Consolidated
- Oversize. 1855-1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Yacqui Copper Company
- Mexico Mines. 1855-1934 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Arizpe Mines (Sonora, Mexico)
  Barranca Mine
  Guaynopita Copper Co. (Guarrero, Chihuahua, Mexico)
  Huacayvo Copper Mine (Chihuahua, Mexico)
  "Old Mines in Sonora and its Mineral Lands (1845)" Yacqui Copper Company
- Miscellaneous 1855-1934 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Oversize. 1855-1934 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Atlanta Mine
  Copper Queen Mining Company
  Oxford Gold Mines
  Tyro Gold Mine Company